Hello, hi friends, welcome to our channel. Friends,
health insurance
is a very important decision because it
protects you from any planned or unplanned medical expense. Nowadays,
hospitalization costs are very high,
which can affect your entire life savings.
Friends, to make this decision
easier, in this video we are going to
review all the
health insurance products of Tata AIG
in detail. We will compare three points of Tata AIG
among themselves and
will also compare the premium at the end of the video. Therefore, make sure to watch this video till the end.
Before understanding the details of the plan, let us
also understand about Tata AIG.
Tata AB Health Insurance Company. Our
majority stockholder is Tata Group, which is a
very reliable brand and
their stake here is 76%. St. Martin's is of
IG Group, which is an American
multinational bank and is also a reliable
company. Both are
very good friends in the insurance sector, hence we
can trust their products.  It was
established in 2017 and as of today
it is one of the top
most insurance companies in India. If we
look at the data of IRDA, which is India's insurance related government body, then Tata AIG Group's
nearest claim ratio in health insurance is 67.
Your data was last updated
in December 21. These figures show how much the
company distributed
back the premium collected from its customers
during claims.
For any good company, this ratio should be
between 52-90 percent. Let's
move ahead without any delay and see the
details of the plans. Minutes Aigo has two
popular health insurance plans. The first one is
Medicare and the second one is Medicare Junior.
Medi Care comes at a slightly lower budget and
Medical Premier is loaded with some more features.
Let's understand these features in detail. First of all, let's
talk about the overall claim ratio. It
tells what your maximum LGB is going to be at the time of the plan.
If we
talk here, the minimum policy of Medicare
starts.  It is free of cost and the maximum
amount you can take is up to Rs. 1 lakh. If we
talk about medical premium, the policy
starts from Rs. 5 lakh and the maximum
policy amount is Rs. Felt sure friends,
both the policies are available for individual and family.
If you take a family plan, then the
mixture is a
combined insurance part for the entire family. Print
Next, let's talk about hospitalization
expenses. If your hospitalization is for
more than 24 hours, then all your
medical expenses are covered. This
includes diagnostic charges,
pages, room rent plus your condition, medicine
charges, etc. The good thing is that
consumer pay is included in Tata Insurance,
which is not the case in many health insurance companies.
And here,
single window AC room is covered in both the policies and there is no
difference in hospitalization expenses. Let's talk about
hospitalization expenses. If you get
hospitalized, then even before that,
medical expenses like medicine are
covered. Here, you get this cover in both the policies.
If we talk about hospitalization, then this
In both the policies, Noida does a very good
thing, that is,
if you do not make any claim for the entire period, then you
automatically
subscribe for it and if you initiate any claim for the entire 2 years, then
it will automatically
double after 2 years, after that it will not
fall further, but if you click on any claim, then
it will fall back to the same rate at
which it was increased, so let's
understand with an example, we
took a tempered glass policy for ourselves and could
not make any claim in the first year,
when we went to renew it, then automatically
our time will be lost, and if no
claim is made even for two years, then it will
automatically increase to 80, if we
click on urs, then it
cannot be subscribed, let's talk about the
benefit that if you are doing it and your claim is
completed, then automatically
in the next year, 100 percent is redeemed for
that policy for the house and friends, the
best thing here is that Tata ABC allows you to
use it again for the same person as well  is ordering which is a very
good thing and it is always there in the company's policy
that you can
subscribe to the
treatment by clicking on the
subscribe button and see the policy document.
Friends, now let's talk about
media treatment at home. If you are
undergoing home treatment and cannot subscribe to a medical practitioner or the
doctor is
not available in the hospital, then you
can use this feature, but here the
subscription should be more than 32 rupees. Front
Neck. Let's talk about ambulance cover, if
you are shifted to the hospital by road ambulance, then
you have the
heart of the ambulance here. If you
talk about Medicare, then here the limit is 300 per
hospitalization and in Medicare Premier the
limit is 100 per hospitalization. Front Neck. Let's
talk about organ donor expenses,
if you have an organ transplant, you have the
medical and surgical expenses of the donor at the
time of hospitalization, that
is also covered in this policy and both of those medical
premiums have a close loop setting. Front
Neck. Let's talk about maternity cover. The
biggest difference in these two policies is the
maternity cover.  If we talk about Medicare, there is
no maternity cover here,
but if we talk about medical care premium, there is a
tweet from Maternity Express
which is that
if it is a girl child, then the new
born baby cover is not in Medicare but it is
included in the medical premium. Here,
if there are any complications for the new born baby,
then
coverage up to Rs 1000 is available. Similarly, if we talk about the
first year vaccination cover of any child, then there is
no doubt in Medicare,
but the medical care premium is where there is a
limit. If it is a boy child, if he
subscribes to the channel or treatment, which he subscribes to for
consultation in the patient department, then there is no
problem here, but
in Medical Premier, there is a limit here, you
get it, you click on continue, it is for
everyone like youth etc., then it
is covered in this policy. Let us talk about
preventive health checkup, you can
use it after two clears and the
limit here is one per cent of meat or again
Whichever is less than the ground, there is a special benefit.
Emergency Air Ambulance: If you have to be airlifted
due to any emergency, then
this benefit is available, but you will get it only
in Medicare Premier and
this benefit is not available in Medicare. Let's talk about
OPD dental treatment, which you can use
in root canal extraction fillings, here the limit is 1000 per
share, but this is available to you
after two years of taking the policy, hence this feature
is available only in Medicare Premier and
not in Medicare. The next feature is Delhi
Cash for Choosing Share Accommodation. If you opt
for a shared room, then you
get an extra ₹2000 per deck.
Friends, the next feature is this Delhi
company now Cover Child Quite Well Near. If
a small child is hospitalized,
then any adult accompanying him will
get it at Twenty Third A, New Delhi Cantt. The
next feature is Prolonged
Hospitalization Benefit. If your
hospitalization exceeds 10 days, then
you will get one  You will get a cent of your time in
short, but it is not available in the benefited year
and it is
available only in Medical Premier. Friends, the benefit
is vaccination cover. You
get coverage for these options after two years.
Some examples are HPV or
Hepatitis B. Here, if you need to
get typhoid or anti-rabies vaccine, there
is no waiting period. Friends, the
next feature is bariatric surgery. If
you have been advised by a medical expert for weight loss
and this is life-threatening, then
you can also use this option. The
next benefit is global cover. If you are
diagnosed in India and
want to go abroad for treatment, then
that is also covered. But here you will have to first get
approval from the company. Along with this,
you will only get basic insurance and curative bonus here.
You do
not get the option of restore benefit. Apart from this,
in this option you only
get the benefit of hospitalization expenses.
Exclusions before taking any of these policies  It is
important to understand that the first solution is the policy
coverage. To get any clean policy,
you will have to wait for 30 days after taking the policy.
Except in case of accident, if we
talk about existing insurance, then there is a
waiting period for Twenty20 matches.
For some certainties like torch light, Aaron
hernia etc. and for full lip, you
can see the policy document. If we
talk about pre-existing insurance, then there is a
waiting period in Medicare, so use this platform
and waiting period in Medicare Premier from
these officials. For maternity cover,
this facility is not available in Medicare,
but there is a waiting period in Medical Care Premium. There is
no option for print speed and dental OPD treatment in Medical, but the waiting
period in Medical Premier is more. Let's move ahead
and now compare the
premium. If Ram takes a policy for himself for Rs
5 lakh and here he has
also insured his wife along with himself.
If we talk about Medicare, then the
premium comes here.  2019 ₹5 per share but if
we talk about Medicare Premier then Samsung
in short comes the premium.
As you can see the
premium of Medicare Premier is about
25 percent higher, so you can
choose your plan according to your budget and need.
Friends, I hope you
liked this video. If you have any
query then definitely put it in the comment section. Also, friends, please
subscribe to our channel and ring the bell that you
see on the screen so that
you get my latest video first. Do
n't forget to like and share our video. Thank you and stay
healthy.